<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Sheldon's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://sheld0n.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sheld0n.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-17T21:58:54+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sheld0n.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sheldon Lee]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entry for Week4 &amp; Week5]]></title>
    <link href="http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/02/17/entry-for-week4-and-week5/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-17T19:09:16+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/02/17/entry-for-week4-and-week5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m really sorry I should have done this last week, but after the code sprint I was in San Francisco traveling and shopping&hellip;and it took me another 3 days to go home.</p>

<h3>What I&rsquo;ve done</h3>

<p>Join in the 2-day code sprint at Facebook:</p>

<ul>
<li>Meeted mentor and other team member, getting to know each other</li>
<li>We made a quick brainstorming to think about how to improve the App Inventor. After the discussion there were 9 projects left and I choosed to work on the UI project which is to make the size of the tabs on the AI2 design page adjust automatically to fit the browser window. Yuanyin and I decided to collaborate.</li>
<li>Create a new branch which is named feature-auto_resized_tabs and start to work.</li>
<li>It took 2 hours for us to find out the solution, but we spent the rest of the 2 days to code, compile and fix bugs one after another.</li>
<li>When the code sprint was drawing to a close, I found a UI bug and report it to jose.</li>
<li>Completed the project, and sent a pull requesest. <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O5KTMK3A6y5rMMzg8rxZtMIUO8FCwFFkNpLjjlBUyEM/edit">Here</a> is the document of this project.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Problems</h3>

<ul>
<li>We&rsquo;ve met several bugs when completing the project. To fix those bugs  is not difficult but time-consuming, because if I want to test I had to compile and run the AI2 local server again and again.</li>
<li>I must keep improve my poor English&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<h3>Plan for next few weeks</h3>

<p>I want to keep working on improving the UI. I think that AI2 could provide users with better experience. One possible amelioration is to make the AI2 design page more customizable. For example, users could drag and drop the tabs to realign them, and each pair of tab has a splitter between them that the user can drag to resize them. The possible solution is to use the GWT SplitLayoutPanel widget and gwt-dnd(Drag-and-Drop Library for Google-Web-Toolkit). This won&rsquo;t be easy, but worth a try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entry for Week 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/02/03/entry-for-week3/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-03T22:18:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/02/03/entry-for-week3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>What I&rsquo;ve done this week</h3>

<ul>
<li>Went through week 3 and week 4 courses</li>
<li>Setted up the eclipse development environment</li>
<li>Applied for a Weather Underground API key</li>
<li>Studied the Weather Underground API</li>
<li>Decided to work on the Components project after I&rsquo;ve gained a general sense of the three parts of App Inventor, but I still show some interests in the Designer at present.</li>
<li>Been working on my Weather Hub app that will be demoing at the hackathon.It provides the users with 10-day weather forecast according to the location given by the users. The app uses the Weather Underground API to get weather data.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Problems that I&rsquo;ve encounterd</h3>

<ul>
<li>No big problems so far.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Plan for the next week</h3>

<ul>
<li>Finish the Weather Hub app by Tuesday.</li>
<li>Go on learning week 5.</li>
<li>Be ready for the hackathon.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entry for Week 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/01/27/entry-for-week-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-27T20:38:06+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/01/27/entry-for-week-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>What I&rsquo;ve done this week</h3>

<ul>
<li>Studied the App Inventor development workflow</li>
<li>Forked and cloned the App Inventor sources, and run my own server locally(On Ubuntu 13.10)</li>
<li>Completed assignment 1: the App Inventor Stock Quotes Tutorial and Food Explorer Tutorial using the local version of App Inventor</li>
<li>Setted up Eclipse for App Inventor development</li>
<li>Completed assignment 2: modify the Camera components to allow user to toggle the camera light</li>
</ul>


<h3>Problems I&rsquo;ve encountered</h3>

<p>This week things were going just fine except a little trouble I&rsquo;ve had when I was trying to build the App Inventor on my laptop. I&rsquo;m using a 64bit Ubuntu 13.10 and JDK. Thus I had to install ia32-libs for AAPT to work. However, ia32-libs is no more available in 13.10. At last I found a solution on Stack Overflow(<a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/19523502/androids-aapt-not-running-on-64-bit-ubuntu-13-10-no-ia32-libs-how-can-i-fix">http://stackoverflow.com/questions/19523502/androids-aapt-not-running-on-64-bit-ubuntu-13-10-no-ia32-libs-how-can-i-fix</a>). Instead of adding 32bit compatibility, I just installed libc6-i386, lib32stdc++6, lib32gcc1, lib32ncurses5 and lib32z1. Then I built the source again and 2 minutes later the message BUILD SUCCESSFUL showed up.</p>

<h3>Plan for the next week</h3>

<ul>
<li>Build a weather forecast application to demo at the hackathon. The app may use Weather Underground API or WeatherBug API.</li>
<li>Continue to study the weeks 3-5 courses.</li>
<li>Make a choice between Components and Designer.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entry for Week 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/01/19/entry-for-week-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-19T23:10:01+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/01/19/entry-for-week-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I have just finish all of my exams so I got a bit behind on the work. But the next couple of weeks I think I can quicken my pace since I will have plenty of time.</p>

<h3>What I&rsquo;ve done this week</h3>

<ul>
<li>Downloaded and Installed the App Inventor 2</li>
<li>Completed the magic 8 ball tutorial</li>
<li>Started to conceive my app for the demo</li>
<li>Joined in the kick off hangout and introduced myself to the group</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Octopress Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/01/19/my-first-octopress-blog/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-19T21:54:59+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sheld0n.github.io/blog/2014/01/19/my-first-octopress-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Octopress!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
